Nick Wehner

Carmel, IN

github.com/nrwehner nrwehner.github.io/ (317) 903-7214

Service Oriented, Creative Problem-Solver

Well-balanced and experienced business professional with a broad skillset focused on service excellence. Both a strong desire and proven record of quickly learning complex concepts and information including electric power operations, physical power trading, various software platforms, data analysis and reporting, and online training methods. Thrives in a balanced work environment with a variety of task types (analytical, creative, routine) and both independent and team-based work.

- Excellent attention to detail
- Strong drive to take initiative
- Keen eye for problem-solving and solution development
- Excellent communication skills

- Loyal and dependable team member
- Reporting and data mining experience
- Quick independent learner
- Creative analytical thinker

TECHNICAL SKILLS

VBA (SQL), .Net Framework (C#), WebApi/MVC, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Access, HTML/CSS, Visio, Tableau, SharePoint, Allegro (Energy Risk Management)

EDUCATION

ELEVEN FIFTY ACADEMY – Fishers, IN

.Net Framework Coding Bootcamp (C#)

WESTERN THEOLOGICAL SEMINARY - Holland, MI

Master of Divinity – completed 1st year

HOPE COLLEGE – Holland, MI

MI Sep 2004 – May 2008

Bachelor of Arts: Psychology Major Minors: Business Management and Philosophy

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MISO (Midcontinent Independent System Operator)

Nov 2018 - Mar 2019

Jan 2020 - April 2020

Sep 2008 - May 2009

Quality Process Analyst – Carmel, IN

Coordination and Implementation of cross-departmental process improvement initiatives.

ACES (Alliance for Cooperative Energy Services)

Feb 2010 - Nov 2018

Process Control Analyst (Sep 2015 – Nov 2018) – Carmel, IN

Senior contributor to a team of trading control and process improvement analysts. Utilized balanced skillset by performing a wide variety of functions for the team and the company. Served as a key contact for solving complex business process problems.

- Used SQL to write Data Queries and design customized data views within software system
- Developed, improved, and repaired business processes
- Utilized Microsoft Office (Visual Basic) products to design work automation solutions
- Facilitated a team of individuals focused on process improvement initiatives for the energy trading function of the company

Hourly Trader (Aug 2014 - Sep 2015) - Carmel, IN

Team member and shift participant on a desk of hourly traders covering a 24/7 shift managing the power supply needs of various clients. Monitored detailed system information to independently make quick, high-impact decisions.

- Communicated with energy market counterparties to trade (buying and selling) real-time energy bilaterally on behalf of clients
- Communicated with power plant operators and regional power system operators to facilitate appropriate plant dispatch
- Responded to various system disturbances that impacted clients (plant outages, transmission line outages, directives from system operators, etc.)

Trading Control Analyst (Feb 2013 – Aug 2014) - Raleigh, NC

Contributor to a team of trading control analysts serving the needs of clients and internal staff. Balanced daily data analysis work with long-term projects and customer service requests of clients and internal staff.

- Performed daily and long-term power trade verification, analysis, and capture
- Performed daily upload, maintenance, and problem-solving of client data warehouse
- Reviewed trade data queries, investigating discrepancies, and assisting with query writing
- Responded to client requests, including support of risk system use and trade data accuracy

Training Specialist (Feb 2010 – Sep 2012) – Carmel, IN

Collaborated with my supervisor to develop new product offering to our clients as well as our internal staff: a library of online training courses teaching energy risk management, power system operations, and NERC Standards topics. Quickly learned new complex information, converting learning into detailed training material.

- Built online courses by designing and selecting graphics, writing and recording transcripts, and developing and synching animations
- Administered NERC CE Provider Program (continuing education for NERC-certified System Operators) and company Learning Management System (LMS)

The Little Star Center

Sep 2012-Feb 2013

ABA Therapist – Carmel, IN

Delivered behavioral modification programs as designed by clinical staff for children on the Autism spectrum (Discreet Trial Teaching, Life Skills Coaching, Community Outing Facilitation).

PROJECTS

Logit – Eleven Fifty Final Project – An App For Daily Food Management MVC Application – N-Tier Arch. – Database Setup – Front-End Design – C#, HTML/CSS, SQL https://github.com/nrwehner/Logit

BookMarked – Eleven Fifty Group Project – An App For An Online Book Community Web API Project – N-Tier Arch. – Database Setup – Minor Front-End Design – C#, HTML/CSS, SQL https://github.com/gmason0702/BookmarkedAPI

Personal Budget – An App For Personal Finance Management

Side project - a SQL database with a Web API for managing personal finances – C#, HTML/CSS, SQL https://github.com/nrwehner/Personal-Budget